Guide to the Brooklyn Yearbook Collection BCMS.0031
Brooklyn Collection
Brooklyn Yearbook Collection
1849-2016
Brooklyn Collection
BCMS.0031
36.0 Linear Feet
A collection of yearbooks from Brooklyn schools.
Scope and Contents
The Brooklyn Yearbook Collection spans over 100 years of Brooklyn educational history. In addition to the class listings and photographs that are useful in genealogical research, the yearbooks provide a wealth of information about academics, clubs, athletic groups, and student activities in Brooklyn in the 19th and 20th centuries. Many of the publications included in this collection are compendiums of student artwork and writing, with visually striking design and content. The collection is consistently growing due to active acquisitions and donations.
Access
Open to researchers without restriction.
Provenance
This is a composite collection from many different sources that include both purchases and donations.
Arrangement
The yearbooks are arranged alphabetically by school name. Each school's yearbooks are arranged chronologically on the shelf. The yearbooks' titles are noted, but do not affect the physical arrangement.
Related Materials
Brooklyn schools collection (1985.054)
Brooklyn Historical Society ephemera collection (ARC.272) and Brooklyn Ephemera collection (BCMS.0007): Many of the schools listed here are also represented in our ephemera files, which contain graduation ceremony programs, report cards, invitations, and other materials.
Brooklyn High School Newspaper collection (BCMS.0030): A collection of publications from Brooklyn schools, covering life in the schools as well as events in their communities.
Class Photographs Collection (BCMS.0029): A small collection of group photographs from Brooklyn schools, spanning the years 1904-2002.
Church schools; Private schools -- New York (State) -- New York.; Public Schools -- New York (State) -- New York; School yearbooks
- Abraham Lincoln High School
  - Landmark, June 1935, June 1936, January 1937, January 1938, June 1944, June 1949, 1989 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
- Academy for Environmental Leadership
  - 2010 - 2012, 2014 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
- Adelphi Academy
  - Adelphic, 1889, 1893, 1944, 1951, 1952 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
- Adelphi College
  - Oracle, 1906, 1910, 1938 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
- Alexander Hamilton Junior High School
  - Ledger, June 1929, 1937 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
- Alexander Hamilton Vocational High School
  - Technician, June 1947, January & June 1948, June 1950 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
- All Saints Commercial High School
  - Excelsior, 1948, 1949, 1959, 1967 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
- Arthur S. Somers Intermediate School (I.S. 252)
  - 1989-1998, 2000-2005, 2007, 2008 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
- Automotive High School
  - Crossroads, 1977 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
- Bay Ridge High School
  - Maroon and White, January & June 1941, January 1942, 1944, May & December 1945, February & June 1947, January & June 1949, 1962–1964 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
    Note:
    1944, 1945, 1963 & 1964 are art and literary supplements to the yearbook, not the yearbook proper.
- Berkeley Institute
  - 1942, 1948, 1956, 1958-1961 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
  - Berkeleydian [literary magazine], November 1910 - June 1911 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
    Monthly issues in this time span, bound together in one volume.
  - Lion/The Berkeley Lion, 1965, 1974, 1977, 1979, 1981 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
- Berkeley Carroll Street School
  - Lion/The Berkeley Lion, 1985-1987 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
- Berkeley Carroll School
  - What a Shape We're In, 1989 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
  - The Big Picture, 1990 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
  - Fresh Perspectives, 1992 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
  - All The Pieces Fit, 1993 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
  - Think, Out Loud, 1994 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
  - Connections, 1996 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
  - The Sky's the Limit, 1998 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
  - Millenium, 2000 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
  - Defining Us, 2001 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
  - Good Times, 2002 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
  - A Work in Progress, 2003 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
  - Metamorphosis, 2006 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
  - Sui Generis, 2007 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
  - Transitions, 2008 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
  - Express Yourself, 2009 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
  - Filling the Blanks, 2013 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
- Bishop Ford Central Catholic High School
  - Pagoda, 1980-1985, 1987, 1988, 1991, 1993, 1994, 1996, 1997, 1999, 2001–2013 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
- Bishop Loughlin Memorial High School
  - Loughlinite, June 1946, 1949, 1954–1957, 1960 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
- Boys and Girls High School
  - Students' Centennial Reader, 1979 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
- Boys High School
  - Red and Black, 1899–1901, 1908, 1909–1910, 1912, 1916, June 1928 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
  - Senior Recorder, January 1935, June 1937, June 1941, June 1943, January 1950, 1960, 1961, 1963, 1964 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
  - Paragon, 1962 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
- Brooklyn College
  - Broeklundian, 1933-1938, 1940-1946, 1948, 1950-1954, 1994 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
- Brooklyn College of Pharmacy
  - Crimson and Gold, 1923 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
- Brooklyn Evening High School
  - Evening Star, 1914-1916 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
- Brooklyn Female Academy
  - Messenger Bird, 1849 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
- Brooklyn Friends School
  - Friends School, 1929, 1930 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
  - Life, 1934, 1936 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
  - Senior, 1938 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
  - Blue and Gray, 1937, 1939 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
  - Image, 1960, 1962 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
  - Brooklyn Friends, 1985, 1986, 2013, 2016 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
- Brooklyn Hospital School of Nursing
  - Starch and Stripes, 1957 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
- Brooklyn Preparatory
  - Blue Book, 1940-1943 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
- Brooklyn High School of Automotive Trades
  - Headlight, 1948 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
- Brooklyn Technical High School
  - Survey, June 1925, January 1928, January 1929, January 1930, January 1931, January 1932 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
  - Blueprint, 1933-1990 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
    Scope and Contents
    June 1933, January & June 1934, June 1935, June 1936, January & June 1937, January & June 1938, January 1939, January & June 1941, January & June 1942, January & June 1943, January 1945, January 1946, June 1947, June 1948, January 1949, January 1950, January 1951, January 1952, January 1953, January 1954, January 1955, January 1957, January & June 1958, January 1959, January 1960, 1965, 1978, 1990
- Bushwick High School
  - Bushwick Beacon, 1915 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
  - Senior Year Book, June 1925, January 1930 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
  - Oriole, January 1940, January 1944, January 1946, 1947, 1955, 1959, 1960-1968 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
  - Drummer, 1983 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
- Canarsie High School
  - Looking Glass, 1963, 1977-1979, 1981-1986, 1990, 1992-1995, 1998, 2000-2002, 2004, 2010 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
- Cathedral College of Immaculate Conception
  - Cathedral Annual, 1940, 1941, 1946, 1947, 1950, 1951 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
- Charles O'Dewey J.H.S. (M.S. 136)
  - Reflections, 1969, 1971, 1972, 1975-1982, 1984-1987, 1992, 2000 -2008, 2010, 2011, 2013 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
- Clara Barton Vocational High School / High School for Health Professions
  - Bartonian, June 1959, June 1962, 1970, 1984 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
- David A. Boody JHS Science-Music-Art
  - Beacon, 1990 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
- East Midwood Jewish Center
  - Sefer Hashonoh, 1939 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
- East New York Vocational School
  - Crossroads, 1944-1964 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
    June 1944, January 1945, January 1946, January 1947, January 1948, June 1948, January 1949, January 1950, January 1951, June 1951, January 1952, June 1952, June 1953, June 1954, June 1955, June 1956, June 1957, June 1958, June 1959, June 1960, June 1961, June 1962, June 1963, June 1964
- Eastern District High School
  - Eastern, June 1936, June 1937, January 1943, January 1947 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
  - Knight, 1972 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
- E. B. Shallow Intermediate School [Shallow Junior High School]
  - Shallow Bugle, 1990 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
  - The Trumpet, June 1933 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
- Edward R. Murrow High School
  - Perspectives, 1995 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
- Eli Whitney Vocational High School
  - Torch, 1963-1965 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
- Erasmus Hall High School
  - Flying Dutchman, 1901, 1911, 1920 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
  - Arch, 1934, June 1935, June 1937, June 1940, January 1942, 1943, January 1945, June 1946, 1954, 1959 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
- The Flatbush School
  - Maroon and White, June 1924 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
- Fontbonne Hall
  - Fontbonne, 1948, 1960, 1961 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
- Fort Hamilton High School
  - Tower, 1947, January 1949, 1962-1970, 1973-1977, 1988, 1995, 1997 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
- Franklin K. Lane High School
  - Senior Echoes, June 1932, January 1935, 1938, January 1939, January 1949, June 1949, 1960-1963 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
- George Westinghouse Vocational High School
  - Torch, 1964-1966, 1969-1970, 1972-1975, 1978-1982, 1984-1986, 1990, 1992-1994, 1999, 2003-2005, 2007, 2009-2010, 2013 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
- Girls High School
  - Triennial, 1910, 1913 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
  - Blue and Gold
    - Vols. 1, 2, 3/4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 11, 12, 14, 15, 1915-1930, 1933-1947 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
    - Bound individual years, 1938, June 1950, 1951, 1952, 1953, 1954, 1955, 1956, June 1957, 1957, 1958, 1959, 1960, June 1961, June 1962, June 1963 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
    - Unbound in document box, 1922, 1923, 1931-1934, 1943-1946, 1948, 1956 (Cabinet Morgue shelves)
  - Interlude, 1934 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
- James Madison High School
  - Log/Senior Log, 1932-2013 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
    1932, June 1933, January 1934, 1935, January 1936, January & June 1937, 1938, June 1939, January & June 1940, January 1941, June 1942, 1943, January 1945, January 1946, January & June 1948, January 1950, June 1951, 1952, June 1954, 1956, 1959-1961, 1968, 1971, 1974, 1985, 1988 – 1991, 1993, 1996, 1997, 1999, 2000, 2001, 2003, 2004, 2005, 2007, 2009, 2010, 2011, 2012, 2013
    Immediate Source of Acquisition
    1932 copy gift of the family of Seymour Silverman.
- John M. Coleman Junior High School
  - Comet, 1966-1967 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
- Kingsborough Community College
  - Odyssey, 1998 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
- Lafayette High School
  - Legend, 1941, January 1943, 1949, 1951, 1953, 1954, 1956, 1957, 1959, 1963-1965 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
- Long Island College of Medicine
  - Lichonian, 1948, 1949 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
- Long Island University
  - Sound, 1948, 1966, 1967, 1992 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
- Luis Munoz Marin School (P.S. 314)
  - 1990-2002, 2004, 2005 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
  - Dual Language Gifted Academy Magazine, 1994 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
- Manual Training High School/John Jay High School
  - Manualite, 1911, 1913, 1914 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
  - Manual Anvil, 1921 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
  - Prospect
    - Vol. 1, 1905-1906 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
    - Vol. 11, 1914-1915 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
    - Bound individual years, 1916-1923, 1925–1927, January 1928, 1929-1941, 1942, 1944-1981, 1983-1984, 1986-1988, 1990-1992, 1998–2001 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
    - Unbound copies in document boxes, 1905, 1908-1912, 1916-1927, 1929-1944, 1948-1954 (Cabinet Morgue shelves)
- Math and Science Exploratory School (M.S. 447)
  - 2015-2016 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
- Maxwell Teachers Training College
  - Chalk Marks, 1929, January 1933 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
- Midwood High School
  - Epilog, 1942, 1943, January 1946, January & June 1947, June 1948, January 1949, 1950, June 1951, 1956, 1957, 1990, 2001 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
- Montauk Junior High School
  - Wigwam, 1936, June 1952 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
- Most Holy Trinity High School
  - Triad, 1957 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
- New Utrecht High School
  - Comet, January 1932, January 1935, January 1936, 1938, 1939, June 1941, January 1942, January 1948, 1952, January 1953, 1957, 1965, 1968 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
- Packer Collegiate Institute
  - The Packer Pelican, 1976, 1979, 1981 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
- Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn
  - Polywog, 1887, 1898 - 1901, 1904, 1905, 1908, 1911, 1923, 1952, 1955, 1959, 1962, 1983 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
- Polytechnic Preparatory Country Day School
  - Polyglot, 1901-1903, 1905, 1906, 1908-1911, 1913-1916, 1918-1921, 1923-1926, 1929-1931, 1933-1936, 1938-1941, 1943-1946, 1948-1951, 1953-1956, 1958-1976, 1978-1981, 1983-1986, 1988-1991, 1993-2006, 2009-2012 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
- Pratt Institute
  - Annual, 1912 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
  - Souvenir, 1910-1911 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
  - Prattonia, 1932, 1950 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
- Prospect Heights High School
  - Cardinal, 1959-1964 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
- Samuel J. Tilden High School
  - Senior Classic/Senior Class, 1933, 1935 - 1938, 1940, January 1941, 1942, 1943, 1944, 1946, 1950, 1967, 1969 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
- Sarah J. Hale Vocational High School
  - Mannequin, 1959 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
  - Hale Horizons, 1960-1963 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
- School of Journalism and Technology (P.S. 506)
  - Be the Difference, 2014-2015 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
- Seth Low Junior High School
  - Spectator, 1950, 1998 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
- Sheepshead Bay High School
  - Topaz, 1961-1967, 1974, 1991 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
- St. Agnes Seminary
  - 1980
  - The Agnesian, 1947 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
- St. Ann's School
  - 1987, 2005, 2006 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
- St. Augustine Diocesan High School
  - The Lance, 1956 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
- St. Edmund Preparatory High School
  - Canterburian, 2002 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
- St. Francis College
  - Franciscan, 1957, 1958 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
- St. Francis Preparatory School
  - San Fran, 1946 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
- St. Francis Xavier Academy
  - Gateway, 1957, 1958, 1959 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
- St. John's Preparatory School
  - Prep Shadows, 1941, 1942, 1959-1961, 1964-1966 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
  - Prep Powwow (Volume 1, Number 1), June 1942 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
- St. John's University School of Law
  - The Liber, 1931 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
  - Res Gestae, 1958 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
- St. John's University College of Business Administration
  - Closing Entry, 1963 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
- St. John's University Teachers College
  - The Warrior, 1951, 1954 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
- St. Joseph's College for Women
  - Footprints, 1928, 1937, 1939, 1962-1965 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
- St. Joseph's Commercial High School
  - Parmentier, 1956, 1957 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
- Saint Mary's Hospital School of Nursing
  - 1952 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
- Saint Saviour High School
  - 1952 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
  - Thabor, 1958-1961 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
- Thomas Jefferson High School
  - Flambeau, June 1934 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
  - Flashes, 1929 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
  - Etchings, 1930 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
  - Soundings, 1928 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
  - Wings, 1928, January 1929 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
  - Aurora, 1937, June 1938, January 1940, January 1941, June 1942, January 1943 1945, June 1947, 1949-1950, 1960, 1961, 1963, 1986 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
  - Pieces of Eight, June 1927 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
- William H. Maxwell Vocational High School
  - Crystal, 1970, 1973, 1993 (Cabinet 3C shelves)
- Winthrop Junior High School
  - Winthrop Owl, June 1954 and 1957 (Cabinet 3C shelves)